Constance Walker Papers
Constance Walker Papers
1939-1975
Walker, Constance.
6.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, artist (1898-1975). Collection contains correspondence (1942-1973); scrapbooks (1940-1972); manuscript and published poems; memorabilia, including articles about Constance Walker, and photographs. Notable correspondents include Alben Barkley, Hubert H. Humphrey, John V. Lindsay, Edward R. Murrow, Eleanor Roosevelt, Adlai Stevenson, and Harry S. Truman.
148726
Biographical History
Constance Walker (1898-1975) was an award-winning American poet and artist.
Walker was born in 1898 in Englewood, New Jersey. While still a child she moved to California where she remained for the rest of her life. Her creative activity began around 1940 when a long, illness limited her physical capacity. The desert, where she spent her convalescence, had a great influence on her poetry. The Courage of Joshua, her self-illustrated booklet of poems, shows this influence. Walker is also well-known for her poem "Pray for Peace" which was reprinted in over twenty-five different publications, used on radio programs, and set to music by Edith Van Gilluwe.
In addition to publishing her poetry in numerous poetry journals, anthologies and newspapers, Walker has also designed and written greetings for card companies such as Hallmark.
Walker has received many awards and citations for her poetry and has been listed by such publications as Marquis Who's Who in American Women (2nd and 4th editions), Dictionary of International Biography (1964-1965), and International Who's Who in Poetry (1958, 1970-1971).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Constance Walker Papers consist of artwork, biographical material, correspondence, memorabilia, personal files, published material, scrapbooks, subject files and writings. Because the material arrived in three separate accessions which have not been physically integrated, related material may be scattered in several different boxes. Material is listed in a logical, rather than physical, order in the inventory below.
Artwork contains prints of Antelope Valley and other items.
Correspondence includes both incoming and outgoing. Letters of note include those from the following:
A. W. Barkley, 7 Aug 1952
Hubert Humphrey, 3 Jun 1960
John V. Lindsay, 8 Aug 1972
Edward R. Murrow, 7 Sep 1956
Eleanor Roosevelt, 30 Dec 1957 and 23 Dec 1946
Adlai Stevenson, 20 Dec 1952, 20 Apr 1954, 27 Oct 1960, and 3 Jan 1964
Harry S. Truman, 10 Feb 1953
Memorabilia contains awards and greeting cards.
Personal records contains lists of book donations and published poems, and membership reports of the National League of American Pen Women spanning thirty years.
Published material contains material about Walker; published material by Walker is located in Writings, in the subseries Published material.
Scrapbooks include general scrapbooks as well as three volumes relating to specific works: The Courage of Joshua, "Pray for Peace," and "Chaparral."
Subject files include Christmas cards, church programs in which Walker's work appears, photographs, and addition material related to The Courage of Joshua and Pray for Peace.
Writings, the largest part of the collection, includes jokes, verses for Hallmark Cards, and other items in addition to the substantial amount poetry of various forms (haikus, quatrains, and even a few set to music). Formats include typescripts and published material such as magazines, newspaper clippings, and anthologies in which Walker's work appears.
Arrangement of the Collection
Because the collection consists of several accessions which have not been physically integrated, arrangement varies. In general, material is arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Women Authors; Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Lindsay, John V. (John Vliet); Murrow, Edward R.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Walker, Constance.; Women artists -- United States.; Women poets, American.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Poems.; Scrapbooks.; Artists.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Artwork
  - Prints of Antelope Valley (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1953 (Box 1)
- Biographical data
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Outgoing, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1942-1973 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  See also Scrapbooks.
  - Awards, 1939-1975 (Box 1)
  - Awards, 1951-1971 (Box 1)
  - Awards, 1965-1972 (Oversize 1)
  - Awards, 1968-1971 (Box 5)
  - Greeting cards (Box 5)
- Personal records
  - Book donations, 1973 (Box 1)
  - List of poems accepted and published (Box 1)
  - Member achievement reports for National League of American Pen Women, 1948-1975 (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Articles about Constance Walker (Box 5)
  - Material by Constance Walker, See Writings: Poems: Published material for published material by Walker.
- Scrapbooks
  - The Courage of Joshua (Box 1)
  - Greetings (Box 1)
  - Pray for Peace, 1943-1966 (Box 1)
  - Presenting Drawings and Writings by Constance Walker (Box 1)
  - The Story of Chaparral, 1946-1972 (Box 1)
  - [General], 1940-1946 (Oversize 1)
  - [General], 1943-1956 (Oversize 1)
  - [General], 1948-1951; 1972-1975 (Oversize 2)
  - [General], 1956-1971 (Oversize 2)
- Subject files
  - Christmas cards, 1962; undated (Box 7)
  - Church programs, with Walker's work, 1955 (Box 7)
  - Club programs, The Schubert Club of Los Angeles, 1943-1945 (Box 7)
  - Material relating to "The Courage of Joshua", 1947; undated (Box 7)
    See also Scrapbooks: Courage of Joshua.
  - Material relating to "Pray for Peace", 1956-1957; 1962 (Box 7)
    See also Scrapbooks: Pray for Peace.
  - Photographs of Walker, 1940; 1945 (Box 7)
- Writings
  - Jokes and humor (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Poetry
    - About Constance Walker, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Award-winning poems, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Complete list of Walker's poems (Box 1)
    - Hallmark Cards freelance class, 1968-1971 (Box 1)
    - Hallmark Cards verses, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - Holographs, A-Z, 6 folders (Box 1)
    - Holographs, miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Holographs and typescripts, 1941-1942 (Box 7)
    - Last poems (Box 1)
    - Set to music (Box 1)
    - Song with cover sketch by Walker, "Chaparral", 1955 (Box 7)
    - Typescripts
      - A-F, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - G-Z, 6 folders (Box 2)
      - Cinquains (Box 2)
      - Couplets (Box 2)
      - Haiku (Box 2)
      - Quatrains (Box 2)
      - Slogans (Box 2)
      - Tanka (Box 2)
    - Published material
      - Book by Walker, Cheeriodes, 1957 (Box 7)
      - Newspaper clippings of Walker's work, 1943; 1946-1952,; 1954-1960,; 1962-1964,; undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Newspapers, 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Anthologies containing Walker poems, 13 volumes (Box 2)
      - Anthologies containing Walker poems, 30 volumes (Box 3)
      - Anthologies containing Walker poems, 16 volumes (Box 6)
      - Anthology containing Walker poems, The Spring Anthology, 1963; 1964; 1 volume (Box 7)
      - Magazines containing Walker's poems, 72 issues (Box 3)
      - Magazines containing Walker's poems, 130 issues (Box 4)
      - Magazines containing Walker's poems, 1955-1969 (Box 5)
      - Magazines containing Walker's poems, 1965-1969 (Box 6)
      - Magazines containing Walker's poems (Box 7)
        The American Bard (1945, 1956)
        American Poetry League Bulletin (1962)
        Anthology of Desert Poetry (1960)
        Arizona Highways (1954)
        The Arts (1952)
        The Desert Magazine (1951)
        World Poetry Day (1961-1963)
      - Magazine clippings of Walker's work, 1941-1963; undated; 1 volume (Box 7)
      - Pamphlet, "Food for Thot" [sic], 1955; 1958,; 1964 (Box 7)
      - Reprint, "Corsage of Youth" from The Boston Post (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous booklets, etc., 13 items (Box 5)